boucheron.com 2018-09-05

# Privacy Policy - Boucheron

**Privacy policy related to the following country  : Australia**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

**1\. Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal data about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

**2\. Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data, we do so on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities), with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html

] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party company outside of Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the European Commission, whereas others are not. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, such transfers outside your country of residence or the EEA will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com including ensuring compliance with the Australian Privacy Principles for Australian residents.

We may also share your personal data with third parties in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us.

**6\. Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We store your personal data in hardcopy and electronically (in computer systems operated by either us or our external service providers). We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

**7\. Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

**8\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting directly privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds -_** **where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.**

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes -_** **where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.**

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law. If you are in Australia, you may contact the Australian Information Commissioner (www.oaic.gov.au).

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact [privacy@boucheron.com](mailto:privacy@brand.com). We aim to respond to you promptly.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**9\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**Privacy policy related to the following countries : Brazil, Chile, Aruba, Mexico, US, Guam**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

1.  **Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal data about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected thanks to cookies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

******2.  ** **Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations or orders submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

**_Do-Not-Track._** Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests. You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed in this section (e.g., by disabling cookies).

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data, we do so on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities), with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
5.  **Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who have a legitimate interest in receiving your personal data, specifically and exclusively in order to assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party company other than Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the European Commission, whereas others are not. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, such transfers outside the EEA will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com.

We may also share your personal data with third parties in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us.

6.  **Security**

We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

7.  **Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

8.  **Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting directly privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, in accordance with local legislation.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds_** _-_ where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.

  * **_Information for California Residents_** \- California residents may request a list of certain third parties to which we have disclosed personal data about you for their own direct marketing purposes. You may make one request per calendar year. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. You may request this information in writing by contacting us at: privacy@boucheron.com. Please allow up to thirty (30) days for a response.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact privacy@boucheron.com.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and where permissible under applicable law, we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

9.  **Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**Privacy policy related to the following countries  : Austria, Belgium, Czech Republic, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Ireland, Italia, Bulgaria, Denmark, Finland, Norway, Poland, Romania, Russia, Sweden, UAE/Dubai, Switzerland, Slovenia, Turkey, the Netherlands, Portugal, Spain, United Kingdom**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

**1\. Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal data about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

**2\. Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data, we do so on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities), with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party company outside of Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the European Commission, whereas others are not, such as the US. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, such transfers outside your country of residence or the EEA will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US or CH-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com.

We may also share your personal data with third parties in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us.

**6\. Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

**7\. Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

**8\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting directly privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds -_** where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes -_** where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact privacy@boucheron.com.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**9\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**Privacy policy related to the following country  : Hong Kong**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

******1\. Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal data about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

**2\. Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence. If you have any concerns about your child's privacy, or if you believe that your child may have entered personal data onto our website, please contact us at privacy@boucheron.com. We will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible should we learn that we have collected the personal data of a child without first receiving verifiable parental consent.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data, we do so on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities) ,with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
**5\. Direct Marketing**

From time to time, we would like to send you (by SMS, email or telephone) marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you, but we may only do this with your consent.

We would also like to share (for gain) such data about you with other entities within Boucheron and the Kering group so that we or they may send you information, news updates, offers, promotions, and special events, as regards their products and services, but we also cannot do so without your consent.

If you prefer not to receive direct marketing communications from us in any form or if you change your mind after providing your consent, you may withdraw your consent by clicking the "unsubscribe" link provided in our communications at any time. Alternatively, you may contact us at privacy@boucheron.com to withdraw your consent.

******6\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party company outside of Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf, on a need-to-know basis. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the European Commission, whereas others are not. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, such transfers outside your country of residence or  the EEA will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com.

We may also share your personal data with potential acquirers and their professional advisers in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required by or permitted to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us, in each case anywhere in the world.

**7\. Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

**8\. Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

**9\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting our data protection officer directly at privacy@boucheron.com or by writing to Boucheron Holding SAS, 20 rue de la Paix, 75002 Paris, France.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds -_** **where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.**

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes -_** **where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.**

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact privacy@boucheron.com.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**10\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. If your personal information may be processed for a new purpose not described in this Policy, or may be transferred to a different class of recipient, we will seek your consent. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**Privacy policy related to the following country  : Japan**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal information that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled/used by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

1.  **Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal information about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal information) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal information that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal information to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal information is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal information necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal information may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal information to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal information to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

2.  **Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal information from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal information, we do so on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal information will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities) ,with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal information with any third party company outside of Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis and will be used for the purpose specified in Article 4. Where processing of personal data is undertaken by the affiliated companies of Kering, for their own independent purposes, we will obtain your consent prior to  transfer your personal data to the affiliated companies. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the Personal Information Protection Commission, whereas others are not. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, such transfers outside Japan will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com.

We may also share your personal data with third parties in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us.

6.  **Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

7.  **Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

**8\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting directly privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds -_** **where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.**

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes -_** **where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.**

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact privacy@boucheron.com.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**9\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**Privacy policy related to the following country  : South Korea**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

**1\. Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal data about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

**2\. Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data, we do so with your consent, where required by applicable law, and on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities) ,with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party company outside of Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the European Commission, whereas others are not. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, such transfers outside the EEA will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com.

We may also share your personal data with third parties in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us.

**6\. Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

**7\. Retention** **and Deletion** **of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

When we destroy your personal data, we implement measures to ensure that the personal data cannot be restored or regenerated.  If the personal data that needs to be destroyed is in electronic form, we will permanently delete such data in an irrevocable manner.  Documents, printouts, letters, and other recorded media will be destroyed by incineration or shredding.

**8\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting directly privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds_** _**-**_ **where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.**

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes -_** **where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.**

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact privacy@boucheron.com.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**9\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**10\. Department in Charge of Protecting Personal Data and Handling Customer Complaints**

Our Legal Department is in charge of protecting your personal data and handling complaints related to your personal data.  You may file any complaints related to your personal data which may arise in the course of using our services to the Legal Department with the following contact.

Name of the Department: Boucheron Legal Department

Contact Person: Anne-Sophie Idier Perroud

Telephone Number: (+33) 142444097

**Privacy policy related to the following country  : Monaco**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

1.  **Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal data about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

**2\. Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data, we do so on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities), with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party company other than Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the _Commission de Contrôle des Informations Nominatives **(CCIN)**_ , whereas others are not. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, such transfers outside Monaco will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com and with the prior authorisation from the CCIN when required by applicable law.

We may also share your personal data with third parties in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us.

**6\. Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

**7\. Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

**8\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting directly privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds -_** where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes_** _-_ where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact privacy@boucheron.com.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**9\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**Privacy policy related to the following countries : Malaysia, Taiwan, Thailand, Vietnam**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

**1\. Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal data about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

******2\. Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data, we do so on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities) ,with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party company outside of Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible (including monitoring, reviewing, collecting, processing, using, storing, transferring, disclosing and publishing) by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the European Commission, whereas others are not. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, such transfers outside the EEA will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com.

We may also share your personal data with third parties in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us.

**6.Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

**7\. Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

**8\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction/supplement of any inaccurate/insufficient data relating to you and to request the discontinuance of collection, processing or use of or the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting directly privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds_** _**-**_ **where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.**

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes -_** **where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.**

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact privacy@boucheron.com. In Malaysia, you may also contact our Data Privacy Officer at privacy@boucheron.com or at the following telephone number (+33) 142444097.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**9\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**Privacy policy related to the following countries : China**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

1.  **Personal Data We May Collect About You**

With your consent, we will collect various types of personal data (including sensitive personal data, where applicable) about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

******2\. Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence. If you have any concerns about your child's privacy, or if you believe that your child may have entered personal data onto our website, please contact us at privacy@boucheron.com. We will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible should we learn that we have collected the personal data of a child without first receiving verifiable parental consent.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data (including sensitive personal data, where applicable), we do so with your consent, and on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities), with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
Unless permitted by applicable laws and regulations, we will obtain consent from you if we wish to use your personal data for purposes other than those stated in this Policy.

**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

As described in this Section 5 and in Section 6 below, we may share or disclose your personal data (including sensitive personal data, where applicable) to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal information with any third party company outside of Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis.

We may also share your personal data with potential acquirers and their professional advisers in connection with potential or actual sale of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required by or permitted to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us, in each case anywhere in the world.

6.  **Overseas Data Transfers**

Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) (with your consent) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the European Commission, whereas others are not. We will only transfer your personal data outside of the People's Republic of China (excluding Hong Kong SAR, Macau SAR and Taiwan) where we are satisfied that adequate levels of protection are in place to protect the integrity and security of your personal data or adequate security measures are adopted and compliance with applicable privacy and data protection laws. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, transfers outside the EEA will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com.

7.  **Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We have adopted specific technological and organisational security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

8.  **Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

**9\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold, to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting us directly at privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds -_** **where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.**

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes -_** **where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.**

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with us and with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact privacy@boucheron.com.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**10\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. If your personal information may be processed for a new purpose not described in this Policy, we will seek your consent. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.

**Privacy policy related to the following countries : Singapore**

Boucheron Holding SAS (" **Boucheron** "), company number 572 034 932, with registered office at 26 Place Vendôme, 75001 Paris, France and Kering SA, a French corporation (“ _société anonyme_ ”), company number 552 075 020 with registered office at 40 rue de Sèvres, 75007 Paris, France (together " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** "), take your data protection rights and our legal obligations seriously. This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") describes how we use your personal data collected via www.boucheron.com (" **Website** "), and by other means (e.g., via social media, cookies, etc.). Please read this Policy carefully.

The personal data that you provide may be regarded as jointly controlled by Kering SA, by Boucheron and by the local retail legal entities of Boucheron “ **Store** ”. 

You may be asked to consent to the terms of this Policy when you access, or interact with us via the Website. By ticking the relevant acceptance box(es), you agree to the collection, use, and disclosure (including overseas transfer) of your personal data and (with your consent) to direct marketing, each as set out in this Policy. Otherwise, your use of the Website will constitute deemed consent to this.

**1\. Personal Data We May Collect About You**

We will collect various types of personal data about you for the purposes described in this Policy, including:

  * Contact information (such as your name, birthday, nationality, email address, postal address, telephone number and any other personal data) that you provide by completing forms on the Website, including if you subscribe to our newsletter and register and create an account on the Website;
  * Personal data that may be contained in communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Website or its content;
  * Information from surveys that we may, from time to time, conduct on the Website for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them;
  * Information about your use and navigation of our Website, such as your IP address and other device identifiers, your operating system and browser type, and information about the Website pages you visit, collected by cookies or other tracking technologies; and
  * Personal information collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on publicly accessible social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from other publicly accessible databases.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. Providing your personal data to us (in particular, your personal details, your email, your address and your telephone number) is necessary for supplying services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your personal data is needed to fulfil obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us with any personal data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us from providing you with the services offered on the Website or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failure to provide personal data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not providing the Website’s services.

Disclosure of further personal data to us other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and to properly browse our services with necessary traffic data is, on the contrary, optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Website and of its services. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your personal data to us is required or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is required or data needed for the provision of requested services on the Website.

**2\. Minimum Age**

Protecting the safety and privacy of children is very important to us. We do not accept registrations submitted by, and will not knowingly collect or use personal data from anyone under the age of sixteen (16) years, or any other age limit set out by the law of his/her country of residence. By registering on the Website, you confirm that you have reached the age of majority in your country of residence. If you have any concerns about your child's privacy, or if you believe that your child may have entered personal data onto our website, please contact our Data Protection Officer at privacy@boucheron.com. We will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible should we learn that we have collected the personal data of a child without first receiving verifiable parental consent.

******3\. Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies. More information can be found in our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html].

******4\. Use Made of Your Personal Data**

Whenever we process your personal data, we do so with your consent or as otherwise permitted by local laws, and on the basis of a lawful "justification" (or legal basis) for processing. In the majority of cases, the processing of your personal data will be justified on one of the following bases:

  * processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps that you have requested in order to enter into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation;
  * processing is in our legitimate interests as a business, and our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. Our legitimate interests may include our interest in using customer and Website user personal data to conduct and develop our business activities (including by carrying out standard marketing activities), with current and potential customers and Website users; and in establishing, exercising or defending legal claims; or
  * processing is based on your prior explicit consent, such as segmented and customized marketing activities.

| 

**The purposes for which we process your personal data are the following:**

| 

**The processing of your personal data is justified by the following legal basis:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide you with the services and information offered through the Website and which you request

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
2

| 

Administer your account with us

| 

Performance of a contract  
  
3

| 

Audit the downloading of data from the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
4

| 

Improve and customise our Website, and our products, services and our business in general, such as by tracking your product preferences and interactions with the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to improve our products and services  
  
5

| 

Identify visitors to the Website

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
6

| 

Carry out data analytics and market research

| 

Our legitimate interest to get to know our customers better and improve our services accordingly  
  
7

| 

Carry out data enrichment, such as by analysing your product preferences and interactions with the Website together with data collected from third parties, such as data that you agree to share with us on social networks (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, etc.) and/or that we may collect from publicly accessible databases

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
8

| 

Correspond with you to resolve your queries or complaints

| 

Your prior explicit consent  
  
9

| 

Send you marketing communications containing news, information and updates about our products and services, offers, promotions and special events, and other marketing communications that may be of interest to you (by SMS, email or telephone), and customize your experience with us to your interests and shopping habits and improving our services, notably via profiling. We also may use the data we collect about you to assist us in advertising our products and services on third party websites – please see our Cookie Policy [https://boucheron.com/en/legal-notice.html] for additional information. 

| 

Your prior explicit consent and our legitimate interest in keeping our customers/prospects updated about our services and products  
  
**5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We may disclose your personal data to any of our affiliate companies, or to our service providers who assist us in providing the services we offer, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in performing other tasks, from time to time.

For the avoidance of doubt, we will obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party company outside of Boucheron and Kering for marketing purposes.

Your personal data will be accessible by authorized personnel of Kering, Boucheron and affiliated companies, and service providers acting on our behalf on a need-to-know basis. Transfer of your personal data from your country of residence to third countries (notably to countries where we operate) will be involved; some of these countries are subject to a data protection adequacy decision of the European Commission, whereas others are not. Your personal data will only be transferred to locations outside of  Singapore where we are satisfied that comparable levels of protection equivalent to those in Singapore are in place to protect any personal data held in that location. To ensure the protection of your personal data is consistent with applicable law, transfers outside the EEA will be made pursuant to the EU Model Clauses, the EU-US Privacy Shield certification, Binding Corporate Rules or other acceptable legal mechanisms of which you can request a copy via privacy@boucheron.com.

We may also share your personal data with potential acquirers and their professional advisers in connection with potential or actual sale or restructuring of our company or any of our assets, or those of any associated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

We will also respond to requests for personal data where required by or permitted to do so by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us, in each case anywhere in the world.

**6\. Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our users. We have adopted security measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. For the best possible protection of your personal data outside the limits of our control, your device should be protected (such as by updated antivirus systems) and your internet service provider should take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee that the  personal data you disclose to us will be 100% secure, nor that any data breach will not occur.

You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold Boucheron, Kering or their processors responsible for any data breach unless it is due to our negligence.

**7\. Retention of Your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. We generally retain your personal data for three years from the end of our relationship or from the last contact from you, unless local law requires otherwise. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to the applicable statute of limitations so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

**8\. Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * **_Right to withdraw consent_** _-_ where applicable, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  For example, if you wish to opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications, you can change your settings in your account on the Website, use the 'unsubscribe' link provided in our emails or text the STOP number in our SMS, or otherwise contact us directly and we will stop sending you communications.
  * **_Right of access, rectification and erasure_** _-_ you have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of any of your personal data that we may hold and to information about how we have used or disclosed your personal data in the previous 12 months and to request correction of any inaccurate data relating to you and to request the deletion of your personal data under certain circumstances. You can see and update most of this data yourself online, or by contacting our Data Protection Officer directly at privacy@boucheron.com.
  * **_Right of data portability_** _-_ Under certain conditions, you have the right to receive all such personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and also to require us to transmit it to another controller where this is technically feasible. __
  * **_Right to restriction of processing_** _-_ you have the right to restrict our processing of your personal data where: __
    * you contest the accuracy of the personal data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy; __
    * the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; __
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or __
    * you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether we have overriding compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing. __

Where personal data is subject to restriction in this way, we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **_Right to object to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds -_** **where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process personal data, then you have the right to object to that processing. If you object, we must stop that processing unless we can either demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or where we need to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a justification for processing we believe that we can demonstrate such compelling legitimate grounds, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.**

  * **_Right to object to processing for marketing purposes -_** **where we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, then you have the right to object to that processing at any time.**

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law.

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any complaints or questions regarding the processing of your personal data please contact our Data Protection Officer at privacy@boucheron.com.

Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavour to respond to your request as soon as possible and in any case within the applicable timeframes.

**9\. Changes to this Policy**

We may occasionally change this Policy, for example, to comply with new requirements imposed by the applicable laws or technical requirements. We will post the updated Policy on the Website. We may also notify you in case of material changes and seek your consent to those changes, where required by applicable law. If your personal information may be processed for a new purpose not described in this Policy, we will seek your consent. You are thus encouraged to periodically review this page.
